Alchemy is a science where one understands the structure of matter, breaks it down, then rebuilds it.
錬金術は物質を理解分解再構築する科学なり
However, it is not an all-powerful technique,
as one cannot create something out of nothing.
されど万能の技にはあらず
無から有を生ずることあたわず
If one wishes to gain something,
one must present something of equal value.
何かを得ようと欲すれば
必ず同等の対価を支払うものなり
This is the concept of equivalent exchange, the fundamental basis of alchemy.
これすなわち錬金術の基本等価交換なり
However, there is a taboo in alchemy. Human transmutation.
錬金術師に禁忌あり
そは人体錬成なり
One must not commit this act.
これ何人も犯すことなかれ
I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
この想いを　消してしまうには
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
I want to go back and finish
やり残してるコト
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
やり直してみたいから
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
夢のつづき　追いかけていたはずなのに
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
曲がりくねった　細い道　人につまずく
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
あの頃みたいにって　戻りたい訳じゃないの
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
無くしてきた空を　探してる
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
わかってくれますように
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
犠牲になったような　悲しい顔はやめてよ
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
罪の最後は涙じゃないよ
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
ずっと苦しく背負ってくんだ
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
出口見えない感情迷路に
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
誰を待ってるの？
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
白いノートに綴ったように
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
もっと素直に吐き出したいよ
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
何から　逃れたいんだ
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
…現実ってやつ？
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
叶えるために　生きてるんだって
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
叫びたくなるよ　聞こえていますか？
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
無難になんて　やってられないから
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
…帰る場所も無いの
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
優しさには　いつも感謝してる
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
だから強くなりたい(I'm on the the
(I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
懐かしくなる
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
こんな痛みも歓迎じゃん
Konna itami mo kangei jan
Scar, a man who only targets State Alchemists,
国家錬金術師ばかり狙う男スカーが
エドワード·エルリックを襲う
attacked Edward Elric.
スカーの攻撃に
Although Ed accepted death at Scar's hand,
一度は死を覚悟するエドであったが
マスタング大佐らの介入により
his life was saved thanks to interference by Colonel Mustang and his men.
一命を取り留めた
Ed and Al, who discovered the joy of being alive,
生きていることの喜びを改めて知ったエドとアルは
それぞれの体を修復するため
decided to return to their birthplace, Resembool, to restore their bodies.
生まれ故郷であるリゼンブールに帰ることにした
Yo.
よう
ヒューズ中佐
Lt. Colonel Hughes.
東方司令部の連中　忙しくて来れないってよ
The guys at Eastern Headquarters said that they were too busy to come.
So I'm here to see you off instead.
代わりにオレが見送りだ
That's fine with me, but...
それはいいんだけど
...why is the Major...
なんで少佐が
It's only natural you'd get an escort.
当然だろう
Getting attacked by Scar in your state wouldn't be too pretty, would it?
またスカーに襲われでもしてみろ
その体じゃヤバいだろ
Just accept the Major's kindness.
少佐の好意なんだ
素直に受け取れ
子供は遠慮無用
Children don't need to be reserved.
Don't treat me like a kid!
子供扱いすんな
And Al is going to be on this ride, too, right?
ところで　アルもちゃんと乗ってんだろうな
Of course.
無論
I thought he'd be lonely riding alone.
一人じゃ寂しかろうと思ってな
What the hell do you take my brother for?!
オレの弟をなんだと思ってんだ
おっ 時間だ
Oh, it's time.
Well guys, take care.
じゃあ　道中気をつけてな
If you ever happen to stop by Central again, come say hi.
セントラルに寄ることがあったら声掛けろや
Dr. Marcoh!
ドクター·マルコー
You're Dr. Marcoh, aren't you?!
ドクター·マルコーではありませんか
It's me, Alex Louis Armstrong from Central!
セントラルのアレックス·ルイ·アームストロングでありま
Someone you know?
知り合いか
He's a talented alchemist who used to reside in Central.
セントラルにいたやり手の錬金術師だ
錬金術を医療に応用する研究をしていたが
He was studying how to apply alchemy to medical treatment,
but he had been reported missing after the civil war in Ishbal.
イシュヴァールの内乱の後　行方不明になっていた
Let's get off here, Major.
降りよう　少佐
I have a feeling he'd know something about the transmutation of living organisms.
そんな人なら
生体錬成について何か知ってるかもしれない
Do you know someone who looks like this?
こういった御仁をご存じありませんかな
Wow, you're good at drawing.
少佐　絵うまいね
Drawing portraits is a skill that has been passed down in the Armstrong household for generations.
アームストロング家に代々伝わる似顔絵術である
This is Dr. Mauro, isn't it?
こりゃ　マウロ先生だな
マウロ
"Mauro"?
We were in a tight spot because our doctors were drafted for the civil war.
この町は　内乱で医師を徴用されて困ってたんだ
マウロさんが来てくれて　ほんとに助かったよ
I don't know what would have happened if Dr. Mauro hadn't come.
He doesn't abandon a single patient
no matter who it is. We owe him so much.
どんな患者も見捨てないで診てくれるからな
有り難ぇよ
It's like something flashes before your eyes,
and suddenly, your wounds are already healed.
パッと光ったかと思うと　もう治っちゃうのよ
This must be the place.
ここだな
こんにちは
Hello?
Whoa!
Why did you come here?
何しに来た
Are you here to take me back?!
私を連れ戻しに来たのか
落ち着いてくださいドクター
Please calm down, Doctor.
I don't want to go back there anymore.
もうあそこには戻りたくない
勘弁してくれ
Please, let me go!
違います　話を
No, you've got it all wrong! We just...
Then did you come here to seal my mouth?!
じゃあ　口封じに来たか
No, we...
いや　そうではなく
You can't trick me!
私はだまされんぞ
I'm asking you to please calm down!
落ち着いてくださいと言っておるのです
アル
Al!!!
I had no idea you were hiding out in the countryside under an assumed name.
偽名を使って　こんな田舎に隠れ住んでおられたとは
I heard a rumor you took some classified documents with you when you disappeared.
噂では姿を消す際に極秘資料を持ち出されたとか
I couldn't stand it any longer.
私は耐えられなかった
Sure, it was an order from the superiors...
上からの命令とはいえ
...but because of it, I had to stain my hands by conducting research on such a thing...
あんなものの研究に手を染めてしまって
"Such a thing"?
あんなもの
So many innocent people died because of it in the civil war in Ishbal...
イシュヴァールの内乱では
あれのせいで罪もない多くの人の命が
I can't atone for what I've done, even with my life.
私のしたことは
この命をもってしても償いきれるものではない
それでも　できるかぎりのことをと
So I decided to become a doctor for this town because I wanted to do all I could to pay for my sins.
ここで医者を
Doctor, what exactly were you ordered to research?
ドクター　あなたが研究を命じられたものとは一体
The Philosopher's Stone.
賢者の石だ
The things I took with me are
the research data and the stone itself.
私が持ち出したのは　その研究資料と石そのものだ
You have the stone?! Here?!
石があるのか　ここに
Isn't that a liquid, not a stone?
石って　それ液体じゃ
"The Philosopher's Stone"...
哲学者の石
"The Heavenly Stone"...
天上の石
大エリクシル
"The Great Elixir"... "The Red Tincture"...
赤きティンクトゥラ
"The Fifth Element".
第五実体
They aren't necessarily in the shape of a stone,
just as how the stone itself has many different names.
賢者の石に　いくつもの呼び名があるように
その形状は石であるとはかぎらないようだ
だがこれは不完全品だ
But this is incomplete.
I don't know when it'll reach its limit and become unusable.
いつ限界が来て　使用不能になるか分からん
But it definitely displayed its power during the Ishbalan war.
それでも
イシュヴァールの内乱では十分威力を発揮した
Same with the bogus High Priest of Lior.
リオールのえせ教主もそうだ
His abilities were improved,
even though the stone was incomplete.
不完全品とはいえ
ヤツの能力は確実に底上げされていた
If something like that can be made,
it's possible to perfect it if we give it more research!
それだけのものを作り出せるってことは
研究次第では完全品も夢じゃない
マルコーさん　オレにその研究資料を見せてくれ
Dr. Marcoh, please show me the research data!
Major... who is this boy?
少佐　この子は一体
He's a State Alchemist.
彼は国家錬金術師です
A boy like this...
こんな子供が
There were so many alchemists who gave up their state qualifications after the civil war...
あの内乱の後
人間兵器であることに耐えられず
...because they couldn't stand being human weapons...
資格を返上した術師が何人いたことか
なのに君は
And yet, you...
I know it's stupid!
バカなマネだってことは分かってる
But I'm willing to go through hell until I achieve my goal!
それでも目的を果たすまでは
針のむしろだろうが　座り続けなきゃいけないんだ
そうか　禁忌を犯したか
I see... so you broke the taboo...
I'm amazed.
驚いたよ
You were able to affix the soul of a human being.
特定人物の魂の錬成を成し遂げるとは
You just might be able to create a perfect Philosopher's Stone.
君なら
完全な賢者の石を作り出すことができるかもしれん
Then...
じゃあ
I can't show you the data.
資料を見せることはできん
But!
そんな
You mustn't desire such a thing.
あんなもの求めてはならん
Even if it's to get our bodies back?!
体を取り戻すためでもか
You mustn't!
ダメだ
That is the Devil's research.
あれは悪魔の研究だ
You'll see Hell if you study it.
知れば地獄を見ることになる
I've seen Hell already!
地獄ならとうに見た
ダメだ　帰ってくれ
Sorry. Please, leave...
I've seen Hell already!
地獄ならとうに見た
Is it really okay?
本当にいいのか
It's incomplete, but we could have taken at least the stone by force.
不完全品とはいえ
石だけならば力ずくで取り上げることもできた
Of course I wanted it. I wanted it so badly, but...
ああ　のどから手が出るくらい欲しかったよ
でも
We don't want to steal the only support the people in this town have in order to get our bodies back.
この町の人たちの　大切な支えを奪ってまで
元の体に戻りたくはないよ
賢者の石が作れるんだって分かっただけでも収穫だ
It's good enough that we found out
a Philosopher's Stone can be created.
また別の方法を探すさ
We'll look for another way.
But what about you, though?
そういう少佐はよかったのかよ
Don't you have to report Dr. Marcoh to Central?
マルコーさんのことをセントラルに報告しなくてさ
The person I met today is
a town doctor by the name of Mauro.
我が輩が今日会ったのは
マウロというただの町医者だ
Hey!
君
Dr. Marcoh.
マルコーさん
This is where the data is hidden.
資料が隠してある場所だ
If you still feel you won't regret
discovering the truth, take a look.
真実を知っても後悔しないというなら　これを見なさい
君ならば　真実の奥の更なる真実に
You may be able to reach
the real truth that is beyond truth...
No... this is unnecessary.
いや　これは余計だな
I pray you boys will be able to get your bodies back.
君たちが元の体に戻れる日が来るのを祈っておるよ
兄さん　なんて書いてあるの
What does it say, Brother?
National Central Library, 1st Branch.
「国立中央図書館　第１分館」
なるほど　木を隠すには森か
Makes sense. A forest would be
an ideal place to hide a tree, after all.
There are enough books in there to last several lifetimes.
あそこの蔵書量は半端ではないからなぁ
ここに石の手がかりがある
I can find a clue to getting the stone here.
捜したわよ　マルコー
There you are, Marcoh.
ウィンリィ　ウィンリィ
Winry! Winry!
You've got an old customer at the door!
お得意さんが来たよ
Yo, Granny.
よう　ばっちゃん
We're back!
ただいま
God, what happened to you two?
まあ　なんだいそのナリは
A lot. We're going to need your help again.
いろいろあったんだよ
また　頼むよ
This is Major Armstrong.
こっちはアームストロング少佐
Pleasure to meet you, I'm Pinako Rockbell.
ピナコ·ロックベルだよ
But gosh darn, looks like Ed got shorter after not seeing him for some time.
しかししばらく見ないうちに
エドは小さくなったねぇ
Hey, I'm pretty sure you're supposed to say "got taller" at times like this...
なあ　こういう場合普通
「大きくなったねぇ」だろう
If you really did, then I'd say so.
大きくなってりゃそう言うさ
What did you say, you minimum hag?!
なんだとこのミニマムババア
Didn't I tell you to give me a call
before stopping by for maintenance?!
メンテナンスに来るときは
先に電話入れろって言ったでしょ
You trying to kill me, Winry?!
ウィンリィ　てめぇ殺す気か
おかえり
Welcome back!
Yeah.
おう
んなぁ
My bad, my bad. It broke.
おお　悪ぃ悪い　ぶっ壊れた
"Broke"?
ぶっ壊れたって
An automail of the highest quality... That I worked so hard on...
私が丹精込めて作った最高級機械鎧を
いや　もう粉々のバラバラに
Yeah, to smithereens.
And Al is broken, too?
で何　アルも壊れちゃってるわけ
What the heck have you guys been doing?
あんたら一体どんな生活してんのよ
てへっ
ったく　心配ばっか掛けて
All you ever do is worry me!
I see.
なるほど
So you want to return to Central as soon as possible to get that data, eh?
その資料とやらを手に入れるために
１日も早くセントラルに行きたいってのかい
Yeah. So I want you to fix me up as quick as you can.
そう　大至急やってほしいんだ
うん　腕だけじゃなく足も調整が必要だね
Looks like I'll need to adjust your leg,
too, and not just your arm.
Oh my, seems like you've at least grown a bit.
あら　一応身長は伸びてんのね
Shut up!
うるせぇ
Unlike your leg though, I'm going to have to remake your arm from scratch.
足はさておき　腕は一から作らにゃならんな
Will it take a week?
１週間ぐらい掛かるかな
Don't underestimate me.
なめんじゃないよ
Three days.
３日だ
You'll have to bear with a spare for now.
とりあえずはスペアで我慢しとくれ
Okay.
It's tough to walk when you're not used to the leg.
やっぱ慣れてない足は歩きにくいな
慣れる前に仕上げてやるよ
I'll fix it up before you get used to it.
But seriously...
とはいえ
Materials... Assembly... Connection... Calibration...
削り出し組み立て接続仕上げ　完璧徹夜だわ
It'll be all-nighters, no doubt.
Sorry for being so unreasonable.
悪ぃなぁ　ムリ言って
１日も早くセントラルに行きたいんでしょ
But you want to go back to Central as soon as possible, right?
Then we'll work to make that happen!
だったらムリしてやろうじゃない
But we'll charge extra for the express fee!
そのかわり　特急料金がっぽりもらうからね
It's finished.
終わりましたぞ
ああ　すまないね
Thanks.
I don't see Edward Elric around.
エドワード·エルリックの姿が見えませんな
Yeah, he said that he was visiting his mother's grave.
母親の墓参りだとさ
Major.
少佐
What kind of lives have those boys been living?
あの子らはどんな生活をしてるのかねぇ
手紙一つよこしゃしないんでね
They don't even send us a single letter.
They are famous alchemists, even in Central.
彼らは　セントラルでも名の通った錬金術師です
That drags them into trouble, as well...
それゆえ　トラブルにも巻き込まれるようですが
But don't worry. Those boys are strong.
なぁに　大丈夫です
あの兄弟は強い
Are they?
強いかい　だといいんだけどねぇ
That makes me feel better, at least.
Are those two like grandchildren to you?
ピナコ殿にとって　二人は孫みたいなものですか
I've been watching over them ever since they were born.
生まれたときからずっと見てきたからね
Their father was an old drinking buddy of mine,
あの子らの父親とは昔っからの飲み仲間だったんだが
but he left the village, leaving his wife and children behind.
ヤツめ　妻も子供も置いて村を出ていっちまった
I don't even know if he's still alive.
今じゃ生きてるのかどうかも分からん
Now that I think about it, where are Miss Winry's parents?
そういえば　ウィンリィ殿のご両親は
They died.
死んだよ　イシュヴァールの内乱で
During the Ishbalan war.
せがれは　あの子の両親は外科医だった
My son... her parents... were surgeons.
医者が足りないってんで戦地に赴いたが
They left for the battlefield because there was a shortage of doctors, but...
It was a horrible war.
ひどい戦いでした
まったくだよ
It sure was.
Oh, shucks.
It's about time to start preparing supper.
ああ　そろそろ夕飯の支度だね
You look like you'd eat a lot,
so you can expect a big dinner.
あんたたくさん食べそうだから作りがいがあるよ
Oh no, I can't trouble you any further...
いえ　そこまでお世話になるわけには
飯はみんなで食べた方がうまい
A meal tastes better with more people at the table.
There's an extra bed open for patients, so you can sleep there.
寝床も患者用のベッドが空いてるから　使うといい
This is the only place those brothers can stay, anyway.
あの兄弟もここしか泊まる所がないんだ
Adding an extra guest won't make a difference.
一人増えたって一緒だよ
What about their home?
彼らの家は
ないよ
It's gone.
They don't have a home to return to.
あの子らには帰る家がない
エドが国家資格を取って旅立つって日に
They burnt their house down the day Ed decided to leave this village after getting his state qualification.
自分の家を焼き払っちまった
They probably did it to make sure there would be no going back.
帰る家をなくすことで
後戻りできんようにしたんだろうよ
Let's go back.
帰るか　みんなが待ってる
They're all waiting for us.
We're ba-
ただい
エドワード·エルリック
Edward Elric!
Your innocent love that drove you to attempt to revive your mother!
母親を生き返らせようとした無垢な愛
Your tremendous love that drove you to affix your brother's soul while prepared to throw your own life away!
己の命を捨てる覚悟で　弟の魂を錬成した凄まじき愛
思い出の詰まった生家を燃やして退路を断つ
Your unearthly determination that drove you to destroy your way out by burning down your home filled with memories!
鬼気迫る決意
Accept my embrace!!!
せめて　我が抱擁を
Get away! It's too hot!
寄るな　暑苦しい　やめろ
Stop it!!!
Wow, you guys are at it already! So early in the morning, too!
やってるやってる　朝からご苦労さん
We've been working all night.
徹夜よ
Wow, it's so late and you guys are still working!
にん　夜遅くまでご苦労さん
You'll be done pretty soon at this rate, won't ya?!
この分だともう終わっちゃう
Another all-nighter tonight.
今日も徹夜よ
Wha...
んなっ
Out!
邪魔
３日でやってくれるって言ってるんだから
They said they'd get it done in three days, so wait patiently.
おとなしく待ってなよ
I know, but I just can't sit still when I know a secret to the Philosopher's Stone lies in Central!
分かってるけどさ
セントラルに賢者の石の秘密があるかと思うと
どうにも落ち着かなくてさ
お待たせ　出来たわよ
Sorry for the wait! We're done!
You up for this?
いいかい
Y-Yeah.
お おう
Ready...
いち
Set...
にぃの
さん
Go!
痛たっ
This feeling of connecting my nerves gets me every time.
毎度この神経つなぐ瞬間がイヤでよ
Well, I won't have to deal with this pain once I get the Philosopher's Stone!
まっ　賢者の石が 手に入れば
この痛みともおさらばだ
That's too bad. You were a real money-spinner.
残念だねぇ　せっかくの金づるが
Yeah. There's no need to go through the trouble of getting your limbs back!
そうよ　ムリして元に戻ることないわっよ
And besides, what's wrong with this?
それにいいじゃない
オイルのにおい
The smell of oil, the groaning of bearings...
うなるベアリング
This beautiful form that was designed based on human engineering!
人体工学に基づいて設計された
ごつくも美しいフォルム
Ah, how amazing!
あぁ　なんてすばらしいのかしら
Automails, that is!
機械鎧
機械オタクめ
Machine freak.
Shut up, Alchemy freak.
うるさ　 錬金術オタク
All right, it's complete!
よし　完成
How is it?
どうだい
Yeah! Feels great!
おう　いい感じ
We raised the ratio of chromium this time so it would be more resistant to rust.
今回はクロームの比率を高くして
さびにくくしてみたの
But that makes it less durable, so don't overuse-
そのかわり　強度が下がったから
あんまりムチャは
Hey, listen to me!
って　聞きなさいよ
Al, sorry for the wait!
アル　お待たせ
すぐ直るのか
Will you be able to fix him quickly?
Yeah. There's a trick to it, though.
うん　ちょっとコツがいるけどね
背中の内側にあるこの印が
This seal right here acts as the mediator between Al's soul and this suit,
アルの魂と鎧との仲立ちになってるから
so I have to make sure I don't mess it up.
これを崩さないように
There! Perfect!
おっし　これでばっちり
What do you say we test it out!
やるか　早速
Sure!
It'll get quiet around here.
また　ここも静かになるねぇ
いよいよだね
It's finally time!
We're going to go find Dr. Marcoh's data at Central!
セントラルで　マルコーさんの資料を手に入れる
明日の朝いちで出発だ
We're leaving on the first train tomorrow!
He's sleeping with his belly out, again.
またおなか出して寝てるよ　しょうがないなぁ
Seriously...
You're like his guardian, Al.
まるで保護者だねアルは
It's a pain having such a needy brother.
手間の掛かる兄を持つと　苦労するよ
How old are you boys now?
お前たちいくつになった
I'm fourteen, and Brother is fifteen.
僕が１４で　兄さんが１５
He's so short, the same age as me,
and they call him a human weapon?
私と同い年でこんなちっちゃいくせに
人間兵器だなんて　笑っちゃうよね
無防備に寝ちゃってさ
Look how defenseless he is right now.
Thanks a lot, you two.
二人ともありがとね
What's this formality all of a sudden?
何よ　改まって
You've always welcomed us as family. I'm really thankful of you two.
いつも本当の家族みたいに迎えてくれる
ばっちゃんとウィンリィには
感謝してる
He might not say it, but Brother feels the same way.
口に出さないけど　兄さんもそう思ってるんだよ
Al...
アル
Hey, we know.
分かってるよ　んなこたぁ
You don't need to say it.
いちいち言わんでも分かってる
Granny... Winry...
ばっちゃん　ウィンリィ
Thank you.
ありがと
世話んなったな　ばっちゃん
Thanks for everything, Granny.
Sure.
ああ
Huh? Where's Winry?
あれ　ウィンリィは
Her last few nights have all been all-nighters, so I bet she's exhausted.
徹夜続きだったからねぇ
Want me to go wake her up?
起こしてくるかい
Nah, don't worry about it.
ああ　いいよいいよ
手入れはちゃんとしろだの
She'll just keep on ranting about maintenance and all that stuff.
ああだこうだうるさいから
Later.
んじゃ
Hey, you two.
そうだ　坊主ども
Stop by for a meal every once in a while, will ya?
たまには飯でも食いに帰って来な
We will.
Coming to a place so deep in the mountains just for a meal?
こんな山奥に飯だけ食いに来いってか
Ed, Al.
エド　アル
Have a safe trip...
いってらっさい
Yup!
おう
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
ねえ　君は覚えていますか
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
約束　契り　初夏の風が包む
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
二人　寄り添った
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
無理な笑顔の裏
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
伸びた影をかくまう
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
だから　気づかぬふり　再生を選ぶ
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
テーブルの上の　震えない知らせ　待ち続けて
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
空白の夜も　来るはずのない朝も
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
全部わかってたんだ
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
ねえ　 いつか思い出すでしょう
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
果たせなかった　約束を抱いて
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
二人　歩き出す
Futari arukidasu
丸１日寝ちゃった
I slept for the whole day.
ほんとにもう　あいつが来るといっつも大戦争
Seriously... this place turns into a battlefield whenever he comes.
あっ
Oh.
あれっ
Whoops?
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
賢者の石の手がかりはそこにあった
Clues to the Philosopher's Stone are certainly there.
However, the enemy's evil hand has seized its target,
だが敵の魔の手は　確実に目標を捉え
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
少年たちは　真実の奥の更なる真実によって
and the boys are drawn into a labyrinth by the real truth that is beyond the truth.
迷宮へと誘われる
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
次回　鋼の錬金術師
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第七話　隠された真実
Episode 7, Hidden Truths.
辿り着きたければ　目をそらしてはいけない
If you wish to reach it, you must not avert your eyes.